Finding Aid for Benjamin Fletcher Wright papers CA.MS.00014
Smith College Archives
Benjamin Fletcher Wright papers
1949-1969
Smith College Archives
Wright, Benjamin Fletcher, 1900-
CA.MS.00014
11.25 linear feet (28 containers)
Benjamin Fletcher Wright was the fifth president of Smith College, and a professor of Government. The collection contains official records of the Office of the President, correspondence, speeches, legal documents, press releases, minutes, memoranda, reports, and newspaper articles.
Biographical / Historical
Benjamin Fletcher Wright, president of Smith College 1949-1959, was born February 8, 1900, in Austin, Texas, the son of Benjamin F. and Mary Blanford Wright. His lifelong interest in political science, especially government, became evident early in life with his fascination for Thomas Jefferson in grammar school. He followed that passion through the University of Texas, where he earned his BA and MA degrees in 1921 and to Harvard, where, in 1925, he earned his Ph.D.
He was a member of the University of Texas faculty from 1922 to 1926. In 1926, he married Alexa Rhea and they had two children: David and Janet. Wright taught at Harvard from 1926 until coming to Smith in 1949. While at Harvard, he served as chairman of the Government Department and served on the Harvard Committee on General Education. He was one of the authors of the renowned report published by that committee titled, "General Education in a Free Society" (1945).
During his decade as the fifth president of Smith College, Wright made notable contributions to the honors program and the interdepartmental majors program. He consistently fought for the value of intellectual and educational freedom in the face of McCarthyism and widespread anti-Communist propaganda. Under his administration, the college's endowment was substantially increased, faculty salaries raised and college plant and facilities enlarged. In 1961, Wright Hall was dedicated in his honor.
After leaving Smith, Wright spent a year as a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Science, at Stanford University in California. The following year he returned to the University of Texas as a professor of government where he taught until the year before his death on November 28, 1976.
Wright held honorary degrees from Amherst College, Mount Holyoke College, American International College and Pittsburgh University. The following are a selection of his published titles: The Merit System in the American States (1923), Source Book of the American Political Theory (1928), American Interpretations of Natural Law (1942), General Education in a Free Society (with others 1945), Consensus and Continuity 1777-1787 (1958), editor: The Federalist (1961).
Scope and Contents
The Office of the President: Benjamin Wright Papers consist of 11.25 linear feet and are primarily related to his official duty as President of Smith College from 1949-1959. Types of material include correspondence, speeches, legal documents, press releases, minutes, memoranda, reports, and newspaper articles. The papers are arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
Major subjects found in these papers include issues of Communism and Intellectual Freedom (Committee for Discrimination in Giving, Massachusetts Commission on Communism and U.S. House of Representatives, Un-American Activities Committee); The Four College Cooperation; The Seven College Conferences and Junior Year Abroad.
Related Material
Additional materials may be found in the Personal papers of Benjamin Wright, faculty and alumnae files and published material located in Smith Special Collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc
Materials regarding the Board of Counselors (Box 8) are permanently closed. Permission to view those materials can be granted only by the President of Smith College.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These papers were transferred to the College Archives from the Office of the President after Wright left the College in 1959.
Smith College -- presidents; Wright, Benjamin Fletcher, 1900-; Smith College--Presidents.; Smith College. Office of President.
- A, 1949-59 (Box 468, Folder 1)
  - Academic Departments, General, 1949-59 (Box 468, Folder 2)
  - Academic Departments: Art, 1950-59 (Box 468, Folder 3)
  - Academic Departments: History, undated (Box 468, Folder 4)
  - Academic Departments: Music: General, 1949-55 (Box 468, Folder 5)
  - Academic Depts: Music: Chamber Singers, 1951-58 (Box 468, Folder 6)
  - Academic Departments: Music: Glee Club (see also Alumnae Clubs), 1949-58 (Box 468, Folder 7)
  - Academic Depts: Physical Education, 1947-52 (Box 468, Folder 8)
  - Academic Departments: Physics, (solar energy)1949 (Box 468, Folder 9)
  - Academic Depts: Sciences (visiting ad hoc committee on sciences), 1958-59; undated (Box 468, Folder 10)
  - Academic Departments: Theater, 1950-54 (Box 468, Folder 11)
  - Academic Departments: Zoology, 1950-59 (Box 468, Folder 12)
  - Alumnae Association, 1949-59 (Box 468, Folder 13)
  - Alumnae Clubs, 1954-59; undated (Box 468, Folder 14)
  - Alumnae Association: Cleveland SC Clubs Lecture Series, 1949-58 (Box 468, Folder 15)
  - Alumnae Council, 1950-58 (Box 468, Folder 16)
  - Alumnae Fund, 1949-59 (Box 468, Folder 17)
    General
    see also, Development
  - Alumnae Biographical File (proposed), 1954-56 (Box 468, Folder 18)
  - American Asso. of University Professors, 1950-56; undated (Box 469, Folder 1)
  - American Asso. of University Women, 1951-59 (Box 469, Folder 2)
  - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1956-57 (Box 469, Folder 3)
  - Amherst College, 1950-59 (Box 469, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary 1950 (75th) and Inauguration:Congratulatory Messages (Box 469, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary (75th) and Inauguration: Fund, 1949-57; undated (Box 469, Folder 6)
  - Anniversary (75th) and Inauguration: Observance Committee, 1948-50 (Box 469, Folder 7)
  - Archives and Sophia Smith Collection, 1949-54; undated (Box 469, Folder 8)
  - Assemblies, 1949-59; undated (Box 469, Folder 9)
- B, 1950-56 (Box 469, Folder 10)
  - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1950-54 (Box 469, Folder 11)
  - Bennington College, 1950 (Box 469, Folder 12)
  - Blakeslee, Albert F., 1950-54 (Box 469, Folder 13)
    see also Genetics Experiment Station
  - Buildings and Grounds: General, 1947-57 (Box 469, Folder 14)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Carlile Carillon, 1949-54 (Box 470, Folder 1)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Cutter and Ziskind, General, 1955 (Box 470, Folder 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Cutter and Ziskind, General, 1956-59; undated (Box 470, Folder 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Cutter and Ziskind: Ziskind Charitable Trust, 1954-57 (Box 470, Folder 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Cutter and Ziskind: Correspondence Pro-Style, 1955-56 (Box 470, Folder 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Cutter and Ziskind: Correspondence Anti-Style, 1955-56 (Box 470, Folder 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Dormitories (proposed), 1949-54 (Box 470, Folder 7)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Helen Hills Hills Chapel, 1951-59; undated (Box 470, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Lamont House, 1952-53 (Box 470, Folder 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Lamont House, 1954-55 (Box 470, Folder 10)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Little Chapel Dismantling, 1955-1956 (Box 470, Folder 11)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Riding Ring, 1953-56 (Box 470, Folder 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds: Wright Hall, 1957-1959 (Box 470, Folder 13)
- C, 1949-56 (Box 470, Folder 14)
  - Calendar, 1953-54 (Box 470, Folder 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1950-59 (Box 470, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Endowment for Int'l Peace, 1950-52 (Box 471)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1952-59
  - Chaplain, Office of, 1949-58
  - Charter, Amendment to, 1958
  - Civil Liberties Union of MA, 1950-53; 1959
  - Class of 1949-59
  - Coeducation, 1952
  - C.E.E.B. Social Studies, 1952-55
  - Commencements, 1950
  - Commencements, 1951
  - Commencements, 1952
  - Commencements, 1953
  - Commencements, 1954
  - Commencements, 1955
  - Commencements, 1956
  - Commencements, 1957
  - Commencements, 1958
  - Commencements, 1959
  - Committees, College: Board of Admission, 1949-58 (Box 472, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Classroom Equipment, 1955-57 (Box 472, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Committees, 1950-1958 (Box 472, Folder 3)
  - Committee, Conference, 1952-57; undated (Box 472, Folder 4)
  - Committee (Faculty-Trustee), Conference, 1950-57 (Box 472, Folder 5)
  - Committee on College Education ofFaculty Children, 1947-58; undated (Box 472, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Educational Policy, 1954-56 (Box 472, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Faculty Offices, 1952-59 (Box 472, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Foreign Students, 1950-57; undated (Box 472, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Graduate Study, 1950-59; undated (Box 472, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Lectures, 1949-50 (Box 472, Folder 11)
  - Committee (Central) Planning, 1951-57 (Box 472, Folder 12)
  - Committee (Central) Planning, 1958-59; undated (Box 472, Folder 13)
  - Committee (Faculty) Planning, 1956-57 (Box 472.1, Folder 1)
  - Committee (Faculty) Planning, 1958-59; undated (Box 472.1, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Special Assistance in Written English, 1949-54; undated (Box 472.1, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Teacher Training (ad hoc), 1956 (Box 472.1, Folder 4)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Chronology and Literature, 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 5)
    see also Mass. Commission on Communism
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Writings by Aloise Buckley Heath, 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 6)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Clippings, 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 7)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Corr. With Aloise Buckley Heath, 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 8)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, Feb 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, 1-9 Mar 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 10)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, 10-31 Mar 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 11)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, Apr 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 12)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, May 1-June 17 1954 (Box 472.1, Folder 13)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, 18-30 Jun 1954 (Box 473, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, Jul 1954 (Box 473, Folder 2)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Correspondence re. Committee, Aug-Dec 1954; undated (Box 473, Folder 3)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Investigation into charges, Correspondence and background on named faculty, 1954 (Box 473, Folder 4)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Investigation into Charges, Corr.with Attorney General, Govt.Documents, 1954 (Box 473, Folder 5)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Investigation into charges, Corr.with College Attorney, John H. Finn, 1954 (Box 473, Folder 6)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Investigation into charges, Trustee-Faculty Committee, 1954 (Box 473, Folder 7)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Official response, Alumnae Asso., Jun-Dec 1954 (Box 473, Folder 8)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Official response, Chapel Speech By B.F. Wright, 4 Mar 1954 (Box 473, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Official response, Quarterly article, Spring 1954 (Box 473, Folder 10)
  - Committee for Discrimination in Giving:Official response, press releases and form letters, 1954 (Box 473, Folder 11)
  - Communism in Colleges, 1953-54 (Box 473, Folder 12)
  - Conference (proposed) on Redefinition of Values, 1951-52 (Box 473, Folder 13)
  - Counselors, Board of (Box 473, Folder 13)
    See Restricted Material
- D, 1949-58; undated (Box 474, Folder 1)
  - Day School/Nursery School: General, 1950-59 (Box 474, Folder 2)
  - Day School/Nursery School: Visiting Committee, 1953-55 (Box 474, Folder 3)
  - Dean, class, 1954-56 (Box 474, Folder 4)
  - Development: General, 1949-57 (Box 474, Folder 5)
  - Development: General, 1958-59 (Box 474, Folder 6)
  - Development: Kersting, Brown & Co. Report, 1958 (Box 474, Folder 7)
  - Development: Kersting, Brown & Co. Report, 1958-59 (Box 474, Folder 8)
- E, 1952-56 (Box 475, Folder 1)
  - Eastman, Eva Hills, 1950-57; undated (Box 475, Folder 2)
    see also Student Counselor
  - Employment Office, 1950-58 (Box 475, Folder 3)
- F, 1950-59; undated (Box 475, Folder 4)
  - Faculty, General, 1950-57 (Box 475, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Club, 1952-57 (Box 475, Folder 6)
  - Faculty, Emeriti, 1953-57 (Box 475, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Housing, 1953-59; undated (Box 475, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Salaries: Correspondence, 1955-58 (Box 475, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Salaries: Scales, 1946-59 (Box 475, Folder 10)
  - Faculty, Secretary of, 1953 (Box 475, Folder 11)
  - Form Letters to Alumnae, Parents, etc., 1950-52 (Box 475, Folder 12)
  - Four College Cooperation: General, 1949-59 (Box 475, Folder 13)
  - Four College Cooperation: Astronomy Department, 1953-59; undated (Box 475, Folder 14)
  - Four College Cooperation: Committee for New College (Hampshire), 1958-59 (Box 475, Folder 15)
  - Four College Cooperation: Committee on, 1955-57; undated (Box 475, Folder 16)
  - Four College Cooperation: Cresap- McCormick & Paget Exploratory Survey, 1954 (Box 475, Folder 17)
  - Four College Cooperation: Non-Western Studies Committee, 1957-59 (Box 476, Folder 1)
  - Four College Cooperation: Radio, 1950-59 (Box 476, Folder 2)
- G, 1949-55 (Box 476, Folder 3)
  - Genetics Experiment Station, 1949-55; undated (Box 476, Folder 4)
    see also Blakeslee, Albert F.
  - Ginling College, 1947-55 (Box 476, Folder 5)
- H, 1951-56 (Box 476, Folder 6)
  - Harvard University, 1950-59 (Box 476, Folder 7)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1950-54 (Box 476, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1955-56 (Box 476, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1957-59; undated (Box 476, Folder 10)
  - Honors Program, 1950-59 (Box 476, Folder 11)
  - Houses, 1953-56; undated (Box 476, Folder 12)
- I, 1950 (Box 476, Folder 13)
  - Infirmary, 1950-1959 (Box 476, Folder 14)
  - Institute of International Education, 1949-59 (Box 476, Folder 15)
- J, 1949-55 (Box 476, Folder 16)
  - Junior Year Abroad: General, 1950-56 (Box 476, Folder 17)
  - Junior Year Abroad: England, 1952-54 (Box 476, Folder 18)
  - Junior Year Abroad: France, 1949-58; undated (Box 476, Folder 19)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Geneva, 1949-50 (Box 477, Folder 1)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Geneva, 1951-59 (Box 477, Folder 2)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Germany, 1950-55 (Box 477, Folder 3)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Italy, 1949-59 (Box 477, Folder 4)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Mexico, 1951-53 (Box 477, Folder 5)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Spain, 1950-57 (Box 477, Folder 6)
  - Junior Year Abroad: Toronto, 1952-55 (Box 477, Folder 7)
  - Juniper Lodge, 1951-59; undated (Box 477, Folder 8)
- K, 1950-57 (Box 477, Folder 9)
- L, 1950-56 (Box 477, Folder 10)
  - Laundry, 1955 (Box 477, Folder 11)
  - Library, 1950-59 (Box 477, Folder 12)
  - Library, Friends of the, 1950-52 (Box 477, Folder 13)
- M, 1949-59 (Box 477, Folder 14)
  - Massachusetts Commission on Communism, 1954-56; undated (Box 477, Folder 15)
    see also Committee for Discrimination in Giving
  - Massachusetts House of Representatives, 1950-52 (Box 477, Folder 16)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1951 (Box 477, Folder 17)
  - Massachusetts, University of, 1955-58 (Box 477, Folder 18)
  - McCarthy, Sen. Joseph: Visit to Smith, 1952 (Box 478, Folder 1)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1950-58 (Box 478, Folder 2)
  - Mountain Day, 1955; undated (Box 478, Folder 3)
  - Museum of Art: General, 1949-53 (Box 478, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Art, 1954-59 (Box 478, Folder 5)
  - Museum of Art: Poussin "Venus and Adonis," authenticity, 1954-57 (Box 478, Folder 6)
- N, 1949-57 (Box 478, Folder 7)
  - Neilson of Smith (Margaret Farrand Thorp), 1951-56 (Box 478, Folder 8)
  - New England Association of Colleges And Secondary Schools, 1949-57 (Box 478, Folder 9)
  - New England Colleges Fund, 1955-57 (Box 478, Folder 10)
  - News Office, 1951-58 (Box 478, Folder 11)
  - Northampton: General, 1949-59 (Box 478, Folder 12)
  - Northampton: Academy of Music, 1949-58 (Box 478, Folder 13)
  - Northampton: Arcadia, 1949; undated (Box 478, Folder 14)
  - Northampton: Civil Defense Organization, 1950-58 (Box 478, Folder 15)
  - Northampton: Clarke School for the Deaf, 1947-57 (Box 478, Folder 16)
  - Northampton: Fire Truck, 1951-58 (Box 478, Folder 17)
  - Northampton: Industrial Realty Development Corporation, 1950 (Box 478, Folder 18)
  - Northampton: St. John's Church, 1935-55 (Box 478, Folder 19)
  - Northampton: Tercentenary, 1950-54 (Box 478, Folder 20)
- O-P, 1949-58 (Box 478, Folder 21)
  - Public Relations, 1947-57 (Box 478, Folder 22)
  - Purchasing Office, 1951-56 (Box 478, Folder 23)
- R, 1949-57; undated (Box 479, Folder 1)
  - Radcliffe College, 1950-59 (Box 479, Folder 2)
  - Rally Day, 1949-54 (Box 479, Folder 3)
  - Rally Day, 1955-59 (Box 479, Folder 4)
  - Reader's Digest, 1953-54 (Box 479, Folder 5)
  - Registrar, 1950-55 (Box 479, Folder 6)
- S, 1949-59 (Box 479, Folder 7)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: General, 1950-55 (Box 479, Folder 8)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: Chester Bowles Asian Scholarship, 1956-58 (Box 479, Folder 9)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: General Motors Scholarship Plan, 1955 (Box 479, Folder 10)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: Northampton-Hatfield Scholarships, 1951-58 (Box 479, Folder 11)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: Proctor and Gamble Scholarship, 1955-57 (Box 479, Folder 12)
  - Scholarships and Student Aid: Scott Paper Co. Foundation Award, 1955-56 (Box 479, Folder 13)
  - School for Social Work, 1949-59 (Box 479, Folder 14)
  - Seven College Conference, 1949-50 (Box 479, Folder 15)
  - Seven College Conference, 1951-54 (Box 480, Folder 1)
  - Seven College Conference, 1954-56 (Box 480, Folder 2)
  - Seven College Conference, 1957-59 (Box 480, Folder 3)
  - Shaffer, Mary Mills, 1952-53 (Box 480, Folder 4)
  - Sophia Smith Collection, 1952-53 (Box 480, Folder 4)
    See Archives
  - Student Counselor, 1956-59 (Box 480, Folder 5)
    see also Eastman, Eva Hills
  - Students, 1953-59 (Box 480, Folder 6)
  - Student Government Association: General, 1950-59; undated (Box 480, Folder 7)
  - Student Government Association: Curriculum Committee, 1950-57 (Box 480, Folder 8)
  - Students, Male, 1952-59 (Box 480, Folder 9)
  - Student Organizations, 1949-56; undated (Box 480, Folder 10)
  - Student Publications, 1952-59 (Box 480, Folder 11)
  - Students, Dean of, 1954-58 (Box 480, Folder 12)
  - Studies, 1949-59; undated (Box 480, Folder 13)
  - Symposium: The American Novel at Mid-Century, 1955 (Box 481, Folder 1)
  - Symposium: Art and Morals, 1952-60 (Box 481, Folder 2)
- T, 1956 (Box 481, Folder 3)
  - Tuition increases, 1946-58 (Box 481, Folder 4)
- U-V, 1950-56 (Box 481, Folder 5)
  - U.S.: General, 1957-58; undated (Box 481, Folder 6)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Un-American Activities Committee, Correspondence With, 1949 (Box 481, Folder 7)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC,Background Materials, 1952-3 (Box 481, Folder 8)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC,Trustee-Faculty Committee, 1953 (Box 481, Folder 9)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC,Corresp. Re. Investigation And Testimony, 1952-Apr 53 (Box 481, Folder 10)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC, Corresp. Re. Investigation And Testimony, May-Dec 53 (Box 481, Folder 11)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC, Press Releases and Clippings, 1953 (Box 481, Folder 12)
  - U.S. House of Representatives UAC, Publications re. Education, 1953 (Box 481, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Navy, 1951 (Box 481, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Office of Education: Federal Security Agency Questionnaires, 1951-52 (Box 481, Folder 15)
  - Vassar College, 1950-58 (Box 482, Folder 1)
  - Vocational Office, 1949-58 (Box 482, Folder 2)
- W, 1951-57 (Box 482, Folder 3)
  - Wellesley College, 1949-59 (Box 482, Folder 4)
  - Women's College Board, 1951-59 (Box 482, Folder 5)
  - Women's Placement Bureau, Inc., 1949-51 (Box 482, Folder 6)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1952-59 (Box 482, Folder 7)
  - World University Service, 1949-59 (Box 482, Folder 8)
- Y-Z, 1950-57 (Box 482, Folder 9)
  - Yale University, 1950-54 (Box 482, Folder 10)
- RESTRICTED MATERIAL
  - Counselors, Board of: General, 1949-51 (Box 482.1, Folder 1)
  - Counselors, Board of: General, 1955-56 (Box 482.1, Folder 2)
  - Counselors, Board of: General, 1957 (Box 482.1, Folder 3)
  - Counselors, Board of: General, 1958-59; undated (Box 482.1, Folder 4)
  - Counselors, Board of: Chapel Committee, 1958 (Box 482.1, Folder 5)
  - Counselors, Board of: Davis Ctr. Cttee, 1957-58 (Box 482.1, Folder 6)
  - Counselors, Board of: Health and Infirmary Committee, 1953-58 (Box 482.1, Folder 7)
  - Counselors, Board of: Music Committee, 1951-58 (Box 482.1, Folder 8)
  - Counselors, Board of: Museum Comm., 1955-59 (Box 482.1, Folder 9)
  - Counselors, Board of: Public Relations C., 1958-59 (Box 482.1, Folder 10)
  - Counselors, Board of: Theater Committee, 1957-59 (Box 482.1, Folder 11)
  - Counselors, Board of: Vocational Cttee., 1957-58 (Box 482.1, Folder 12)
  - Personal (Box 483)
  - Personal (Box 484)
- Inaugural invitations and programs from other colleges, 1949-1954 (Box 485)
- Innaugural invitations and programs from other colleges, 1955-1959 (Box 486)
- Engagements and official calendars, 1949-59 (Box 487)
- Photographs and portrait (Box 488.1)
- Reports A-M (Box 488.2)
- Reports N-Z (Box 488.3)
- Speeches, 1949-1953 (Box 488.4)
- Speeches, 1954-1958 (Box 488.5)